# MIGUEL PACHECO

Web developer with extensive experience in building applications and websites, skills in back-end, front-end, and UX/UI design. My experience in the industry has allowed me to develop a wide set of skills.

I have also worked on large and complex projects, which has allowed me to acquire extensive experience in project management and teamwork. I consider myself a curious and proactive person, with a great interest in new technologies and a focus on continuous learning.

My goal is to seek greater responsibilities in a company that allows me to continue growing professionally, providing me with new challenges and learning opportunities, as well as job stability.

## COURSES AND CERTIFICATIONS

- -Scrum Fundamentals Certified
- -Foundations of User Experience (UX) Design
- -Build Wireframes and Low-Fidelity Prototypes
- <u>-Start the UX Design Process: Empathize, Define, and Ideate</u>

# LANGUAGES

English: Between A2-B1
Spanish: Native

### **AVAILABILITY**

Change of location

To travel

Immediate incorporation

Home office

✓

#### CONTACT



MIGUEL.PACHECOG925@GMAIL.COM



MIGUEL PACHECOG



MIGUELANGELPG



771-382-4016

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

### ANL. SOFTWARE PROGRAMMER ERYCIA OCT. 202:

- Design and management of relational databases, SQLServer.
- Creation of stored procedures, views, functions.
- Development of web application with .NET framework.
- Development of dynamic forms with JS, JQuery.
- Requirements analysis.
- Development of web application with React JS.

### DV. FRONT-END KAREM DAYAN MAR. 2022 - SEP. 2022

- Development of web application with Next JS and React JS + Typescript.
- Creation of prototypes, wireframes, and mockups.
- Manipulation of non-relational databases (MongoDB).
- Responsive design and styles with Material UI.
- Creation of APIs with Node JS. Use of JSON web token.
  Manipulation of environment variables.
- Use of version control (GIT, Github).

#### DV. WEB BIZNAGA RISK AND TECH SEP. 2021 - ENE. 2022

- Development of web application with React JS using ECMAScript 6 and Typescript.
- Web design and animations with CSS3.
- Creation of functional and reusable components Handling of global state with Redux.
- Control of private and public routes.
- Consumption of firebase REST API.
- Use of firebase services: authentication, hosting and firestore.
- Handling of non-relational DB (firebase).

#### **DEVELOPER WEB JR.**

VLIM JUN. 2019 - SEP. 2021

- Management of projects using agile methodologies (SCRUM).
- Structuring and layout of pages with HTML5.
- Responsive design of web pages using JQuery, CSS3, JS and Bootstrap.
- Control and validation of forms with JS and jQuery.
- Consumption of web services and APIs and handling of data and interaction within the DOM.
- Design and management of relational databases, MySQL.
- Writing functional and scalable code.
- Use of stored procedures for CRUD in DB Construction of web service with PHP (SLIM).
- Design and sending of dynamic emails using SMTP protocol.
- Creation of PDF, TXT, and XLSX files.
- Dynamic table pagination.
- Development of web application with React JS.

## ACADEMIC BACKGROUND

2018-2022 INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY ENGINEERING.

METROPOLITAN POLYTECHNIC UNIVERSITY OF HIDALGO

2015- 2018 PROGRAMMING TECHNICIAN

INDUSTRIAL TECHNOLOGY AND SERVICES HIGH SCHOOL